<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name></name>
		<update version="1.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zenoverlordian/Aurora-Builder-SwEcky/main/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Omega Warlock" type="Source" source="Omega Warlock" id="ID_SWECKY_SOURCE_OMEGA_WARLOCK">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p> A warlock revision focused on the importance of pacts and a new system for all Chain warlocks. </p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">SWECKY</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/</set>
			<set name="image">https://styles.redditmedia.com/t5_drhrd/styles/profileIcon_k7c7jlvs9ps01.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="SWECKY" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/">SwEcky</set>
			<set name="official">false</set>
			<set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
			<set name="release">20180422</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Alpha Druid" type="Source" source="Alpha Druid" id="ID_SWECKY_SOURCE_ALPHA_DRUID">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p> Since the release of 5e the druid class have always irked me. While the Ranger had it problems, it was still a class I would play. The druid was a class which was supposedly a hybrid class, but felt like it lost a lot of flavour it could have had for it. </p>
			<p> A Little too Wild. A lot came down to having quite a large ability (Wild Shape) which would go largely unused or if the subclass focused on it, it felt extremely weirdly balanced; it went from overpowered to weak, back to overpowered and towards useless in the end. Any druid can still use polymorph to turn themselves into a scouting creature if that is what you want. Removing Wild Shape from the main class opens up a lot of design space for doing interesting things for the subclasses, something I hope you enjoy as much as I have. </p>
			<p> A Part of History. "But it has been this way for a long time!" Some might say, and yes it has, but it severly limits its design space in my opinion and I'm pretty sure I'm not alone in feeling like I'm missing out when I want to play a non-shapeshifting druid. </p>
			<p> Additional Spells? I really enjoyed the Circle of the Spore druid Wizards have created and how Circle spells can make it feel a lot more unique, I've added such to each Circle and made them play into how the subclass plays. The druid class have an unique spell list which sometimes feel a bit too niche, giving them some additional spells help reinforce the flavour of their subclass. </p>
			<p> The Unlimited Elephant in the Room. I've also tried to rebalance the 20th level ability, an ability I've never liked as it was written. I'm still not totally satisfied with how it is and would love to hear how people envision a lvl 20 Archdruid ability would look and feel. </p>
			<p> On the Horizon. I've got plans for more circles; Circle of the Sun (healer focused), Circle of the Swarm/Many (CC focused), Circle of Balance/Harmony (jack of all trades), Circle of the Ethereal (Find familiar and summon focused), Circle of the Courts (fey, illusion/deception focused). </p>
			<p> Remember the Supplements. I've added 4 appendixes at the end of the document; A and B for creating the Circle of the Keeper Companion, Appendix C for Homebrew Spells which I use, and lastly Appendix D with all familiars for ease of access... and it might be important in the future. </p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">SWECKY</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/</set>
			<set name="image">https://styles.redditmedia.com/t5_drhrd/styles/profileIcon_k7c7jlvs9ps01.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="SWECKY" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/">SwEcky</set>
			<set name="official">false</set>
			<set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
			<set name="release">20180422</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Delta Ranger" type="Source" source="Delta Ranger" id="ID_SWECKY_SOURCE_DELTA_RANGER">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p> Took me a while, but I'm finally ready to reveal my Ranger revision, hopefully it stands out amidst the ball pit that is ranger reworks. There's a lot of things wrong with the PHB Ranger, u/Radidactyl put it better here then I ever and could. I released my first attempt almost exactly 2 years ago and it has worked well in campaigns, but it still didn't feel "good enough", it still felt like half the abilities you got were weak or uninteresting. Also, I personally got a heavy dislike for the "auto-success" features which just plains up removes the exploration part of the game. I do think the Ranger should shine there, if they want to, but removing it as an obstacle is the wrong way to go.</p>
			<p> What Makes a Ranger? The question I'm guessing everyone has a different answer to, and a complicated answer at that. Is it the abilities of old that should venerate and keep sacred? Is it the paladin but nature? To me, who started in 3.5e, the Ranger felt like a specialist/martial/spellcaster combo, a mix of rogue/druid/fighter but still finding its niche. In 5e, having a class focused around a niche is bad for gameplay, but being able to choose your niche is amazing for both gameplay and roleplay. So my short answer is; the Ranger is a specialist who can help the party find & bring down specific threats.</p>
			<p> Pack Animal. The Ranger has of course gotten the new Companion creator from the Alpha Druid, but the Beastmaster subclass makes it its own.</p>
			<p> Different Paths. I've moved around abilities, and tried making the power curve feel more natural than it does for the PHB Ranger. Actually having abilities to look forward to after level 7 is crazy, I know. I also moved the capstone from the main class to the subclasses.</p>
			<p> More Than a Feeling. I've also put more focus into Wisdom, it barely felt like a stat for Ranger before, and as such I've made some abilities key of it. Just like Charisma is a great boon for paladins, it is even worth investing in as a primary stat.</p>
			<p> Prepared for the Worst. I've chosen to make the Delta Ranger a prepared caster since the ranger got some very situational spells, which is great but can't really be picked when you are so limited due to just having spells known. Moving Hunter's Mark from being a spell to being part of the class, also helps.</p>
			<p> On the Horizon. Pact of the Unleashed for the warlock is done, but I'm trying to complete 1 or 2 more before I release an update to the Omega Warlock. Not having any plans for a big rework for the time being.</p>
			<p> Also, stay safe everyone. </p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">SWECKY</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/</set>
			<set name="image">https://styles.redditmedia.com/t5_drhrd/styles/profileIcon_k7c7jlvs9ps01.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="SWECKY" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/SwEcky/submitted/">SwEcky</set>
			<set name="official">false</set>
			<set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
			<set name="release">20180422</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>